let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "Which of the following is not a major blood vessel in the cardiovascular system?",
        answer: "C. Spinal artery",
        options: [ 
            "A. Aorta",
            "B. Carotid artery",
            "C. Spinal artery",
            "D. Pulmonary artery"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "What is the main function of the cardiovascular system?",
        answer: "A. Transportation of oxygen and nutrients",
        options: [
            "A. Transportation of oxygen and nutrients",
            "B. Regulation of body temperature",
            "C. Production of hormones",
            "D. Protection against infection"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "Which chamber of the heart receives oxygenated blood from the lungs?",
        answer: "A. Left atrium",
        options: [
            "A. Left atrium",
            "B. Left ventricle",
            "C. Right atrium",
            "D. Right ventricle"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "The cardiovascular system is responsible for the circulation of which of the following?",
        answer: "A. Blood",
        options: [
            "A. Blood",
            "B. Lymph",
            "C. Cerebrospinal fluid",
            "D. Synovial fluid"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "Which of the following is not a type of blood vessel in the cardiovascular system?",
        answer: "D. Tendon",
        options: [
            "A. Artery",
            "B. Vein",
            "C. Capillary",
            "D. Tendon"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "The sinoatrial node is responsible for initiating which type of electrical signal in the heart?",
        answer: "A. Contraction",
        options: [
            "A. Contraction",
            "B. Relaxation",
            "C. Fibrillation",
            "D. Arrhythmia"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "The process by which blood vessels constrict to increase blood pressure is known as:",
        answer: "C. Vasoconstriction",
        options: [
            "A. Vasodilation",
            "B. Hemostasis",
            "C. Vasoconstriction",
            "D. Thrombosis"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "The sound of the heartbeat is caused by the closing of which heart valves?",
        answer: "B. Semilunar valves",
        options: [
            "A. Atrioventricular valves",
            "B. Semilunar valves",
            "C. Mitral valve",
            "D. Tricuspid valve"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "The average resting heart rate for adults is approximately:",
        answer: "A. 60-100 beats per minute",
        options: [
            "A. 60-100 beats per minute",
            "B. 120-160 beats per minute",
            "C. 30-50 beats per minute",
            "D. 200-250 beats per minute"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "The structure that separates the left and right sides of the heart is called the:",
        answer: "A. Interventricular septum",
        options: [
            "A. Interventricular septum",
            "B. Interatrial septum",
            "C. Atrioventricular septum",
            "D. Atrial septum"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "What organ pumps blood throughout the body?",
        answer: "C. Heart",
        options: [
            "A. Brain",
            "B. Skin",
            "C. Heart",
            "D. Lungs"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "What is the inner layer of the heart wall?",
        answer: "C. Endocardium",
        options: [
            "A. Epicardium",
            "B. Myocardium",
            "C. Endocardium",
            "D. Pericardium"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "It is a rapid heart rate of over 100 beats per minute.",
        answer: "A. Tachycardia",
        options: [
            "A. Tachycardia",
            "B. Bradycardia",
            "C. Cardiac",
            "D. Fibrillation"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "What part of the heart pumps blood low in oxygen to the lungs?",
        answer: "D. Right ventricle",
        options: [
            "A. Left Atrium",
            "B. Right Atrium",
            "C. Left Ventricle",
            "D. Right Ventricle"
        ]
    },
     {
        numb: 15,
        question: "________ is classified as a large vein, with a wide diameter of up to 2cm and a length of approximately 7 cm.",
        answer: "B. Superior vena cava",
        options: [
            "A. Aorta",
            "B. Superior vena cava",
            "C. Pericardium",
            "D. Sternum"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "How many hollow chambers does the heart have?",
        answer: "A. 4",
        options: [
            "A. 4",
            "B. 6",
            "C. 5",
            "D. 3"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "It is the lack of adequate oxygen supply to the heart muscle.",
        answer: "B. Ischemia",
        options: [
            "A. Heart Block",
            "B. Ischemia",
            "C. Fibrillation",
            "D. Tachycardia"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "The performance of the human heart from the beginning of one heartbeat to the beginning of the next.",
        answer: "D. Cardiac cycle",
        options: [
            "A. Heart Cycle",
            "B. Diaphragm Cycle",
            "C. Aorta Cycle",
            "D. Cardiac Cycle"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "What is the main pumping chamber of the heart?",
        answer: "A. Ventricle",
        options: [
            "A. Ventricle",
            "B. Tricuspid",
            "C. Ventricle",
            "D. Systole"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "What is the large vessel carrying blood away from the heart?",
        answer: "C. Artery",
        options: [
            "A. Mitral",
            "B. Carotid",
            "C. Artery",
            "D. Vascular system"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 21,
        question: "Thin-walled vessels where oxygen and nutrients exchange with tissues?",
        answer: "B. Capillaries",
        options: [
            "A. Heart",
            "B. Capillaries",
            "C. Pulse",
            "D. Plasma"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 22,
        question: "The valve between the left atrium and left ventricle.",
        answer: "A. Mitral valve",
        options: [
            "A. Mitral valve",
            "B. Artery",
            "C. Hemoglobin",
            "D. Vein"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 23,
        question: "It provides the heart muscle with oxygenated blood.",
        answer: "A. Coronary circuit",
        options: [
            "A. Coronary circuit",
            "B. Capillaries",
            "C. Systole",
            "D. Aldosterone"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 24,
        question: "The liquid component of the blood.",
        answer: "B. Plasma",
        options: [
            "A. Pressure",
            "B. Plasma",
            "C. Pulse",
            "D. Carotid"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 25,
        question: "What is the medical term for high blood pressure?",
        answer: "C. Hypertension",
        options: [
            "A. Hyperacidity",
            "B. Hypersensitivity",
            "C. Hypertension",
            "D. Hyperglycemia"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 26,
        question: "The device that is used to measure blood pressure.",
        answer: "A. Sphygmomanometer",
        options: [
            "A. Sphygmomanometer",
            "B. Stethoscope",
            "C. Electrocardiogram",
            "D. X-ray machine"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 27,
        question: "The condition where fatty deposits narrow blood vessels.",
        answer: "B. Atherosclerosis",
        options: [
            "A. Diabetic",
            "B. Atherosclerosis",
            "C. Coronary artery disease",
            "D. Carotid artery disease"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 28,
        question: "It sits under your lungs and separates your chest cavity from your abdomen.",
        answer: "C. Diaphragm",
        options: [
            "A. Thorax",
            "B. Pericardium",
            "C. Diaphragm",
            "D. Apex"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 29,
        question: "The apex of the heart is oriented towards the?",
        answer: "C. Left hip",
        options: [
            "A. Right hip",
            "B. Right shoulder",
            "C. Left hip",
            "D. Umbilicus"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 30,
        question: "It fills the space between the layers of pericardium.",
        answer: "C. Serous Fluid",
        options: [
            "A. Interventricular septum",
            "B. Pulmonary",
            "C. Serous fluid",
            "D. Tricuspid valve"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 31,
        question: "Inflammation of the endocardium which may lead to valvular incompetence.",
        answer: "A. Endocarditis",
        options: [
            "A. Endocarditis",
            "B. Pericarditis",
            "C. Atria",
            "D. Septum"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 32,
        question: "A wall that divides the heart sagittally into right and left sides.",
        answer: "B. Septum",
        options: [
            "A. AV valves",
            "B. Septum",
            "C. Tricuspid",
            "D. Valves"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 33,
        question: "The narrowing of blood vessels is known as?",
        answer: "D. Vasoconstriction",
        options: [
            "A. Endocardium",
            "B. Aorta",
            "C. Vasodilation",
            "D. Vasoconstriction"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 34,
        question: "Branch from the aorta to supply the heart muscle with oxygenated blood.",
        answer: "C. Coronary arteries",
        options: [
            "A. Cardiac Veins",
            "B. Coronary sinus",
            "C. Coronary arteries",
            "D. Pulmonary Trunk"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 35,
        question: "The larger blood vessels that carry blood away from the heart are called?",
        answer: "D. Arteries",
        options: [
            "A. Cardiac veins",
            "B. Aorta",
            "C. Tachycardia",
            "D. Arteries"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 36,
        question: "It is when the blood flows from the right side of the heart to the lungs and back to the left side of the heart.",
        answer: "B. Pulmonary circulation",
        options: [
            "A. Systemic circulation",
            "B. Pulmonary circulation",
            "C. Diastole",
            "D. Fibrillation"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 37,
        question: "A rapid, uncoordinated shuddering of the heart muscles resulting from ischemia.",
        answer: "C. Fibrillation",
        options: [
            "A. Heart block",
            "B. Systole",
            "C. Fibrillation",
            "D. Systematic circulation"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 38,
        question: "What is the cardiovascular system responsible for?",
        answer: "A. Transporting oxygen and nutrients throughout the body and removing waste products",
        options: [
            "A. Transporting oxygen and nutrients throughout the body and removing waste products",
            "B. Controlling the body's temperature",
            "C. Protecting the body from infection",
            "D. Producing hormones"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 39,
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a component of the cardiovascular system?",
        answer: "B. Lungs",
        options: [
            "A. Heart",
            "B. Lungs",
            "C. Blood vessels",
            "D. Blood"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 40,
        question: "What is the main function of the heart?",
        answer: "A. To pump blood throughout the body",
        options: [
            "A. To pump blood throughout the body",
            "B. To filter the blood",
            "C. To produce oxygen",
            "D. To store blood"
        ]
    }
];



